# Saimon Howlader Software Engineering

≥ saimon@saimonhowlader.com • saimonhowlader.com • 347-927-7626 • Jamaica, New York • saimonhowlader

## **Summary**

Software engineering student with a passion for web development and an interest in microeconomics. Currently looking for practical work experience in an internship. Tutored at several institutions for the past 5 years years with significant experience in designing curricula and organizing teams with an eye for efficiency, but now seeking a full management position within a tutoring center.

## **Employment**

Aug 2015 - May 2016

Math Matters Inc. - Tutor

Jamaica, NYC

- Taught classes to prepare high school students for the Algebra I regents, and the SAT math section.
- Occasionally worked with students from elementary school to middle school, and students with special needs.
- Typically taught 6 students at a time.
- Worked with branch manager to help figure out the best match between incoming students and other tutors.

Jul 2015 - Current

#### Khan's family - Private tutor

Jamaica, NY

Tutored their son (age 14, 8th grade) for the SHSAT, an admissions test for prestigious high schools. He scored within the 5 highest possible scores, and currently tutoring their younger son for the same test.

Jun 2015 - Nov 2015

### Freelance IT, by referral

Manhattan, NYC

- Set up various hardware and trained clients on how to manage their website's content and solved various technical issues such as fixing their DNS listings, transferring domains, transferring web hosts, repairing faulty websites.
- Cataloged all technical information in case any future problems arose with site availability.

#### Clients

Marilyn Church, Courtroom Artist

Ann Gillen, Sculptor

May 2015 - Jul 2015

#### The Runner News - Computer technician and IT support

Jackson Heights, NYC

- Set up their office so the journalists could actually rely on their computers instead of having to work from home.
- They were able to double their team from only 2 people since their office could now accommodate more people thanks to setting up some old workstations.
- Trained a few employees on how to efficiently create backups, share their work, and communicate with the publishing department in Bangladesh.
- Provided on-site support on publishing days in case of technical difficulties.

Skills

Programming languages: Java, Javascript

Front-end languages: HTML5, CSS3

Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash/Animate

Learning: PHP, Spanish Secondary languages: Bengali

# **Education**

York College, City University of New York

2019

**Hunter College Highschool** 

2015

#### Side projects

saimonhowlader.com

Personal website for contact info and technical blog.